<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Aziz Khan</title>
    <link>https://asntech.github.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Aziz Khan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2020 Aziz Khan</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://asntech.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Computational biology without borders</title>
      <link>https://asntech.github.io/post/computational-biology-without-borders/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://asntech.github.io/post/computational-biology-without-borders/</guid>
      <description>I wrote this blog post for Open Bioinformatics Foundation (OBF) and it was originally posted on October 26, 2019 on OBF website. OBF supported me with a travel grant of $1000 to attend the ISMB/ECCB and BOSC 2019 meeting in Basel, July 2019.
Computational tools and software are now becoming the core of scientific discovery, and making it open source and sharing it freely with the community helps to take scientific discoveries to the next level.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My worst Journal shopping and peer-review experience</title>
      <link>https://asntech.github.io/post/my-worst-journal-shopping-and-peer-review-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2019 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://asntech.github.io/post/my-worst-journal-shopping-and-peer-review-experience/</guid>
      <description>As an early career researcher it is not easy to publish your research in a decent scientific journal and with the time passes scientific publishing is becoming more difficult and challenging.
The aim of one of my initial projects during Ph.D. was to integrate diverse types of data to identify new signatures of a newly defined class of enhancers (super-enhancers) using computational and machine learning modeling. Through integrative analysis, we found some new features alongside with many known and ranked them based on their predictive importance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Towards a format-free submission policy: Let&#39;s put science first</title>
      <link>https://asntech.github.io/post/towards-a-format-free-initial-submission-policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Apr 2018 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://asntech.github.io/post/towards-a-format-free-initial-submission-policy/</guid>
      <description>Most academic journals have stringent manuscript formatting guidelines that authors must follow before making an initial submission. This process is extremely time consuming and, in many cases, has to be repeated multiple times for submission to a new journal after rejection.
 Formatting has no impact on the scientific basis of a manuscript, and style plays no role in the ability to judge its scientific content.
 It is, therefore, essential to stop these unnecessary and wasteful cycles of formatting to save time and resources.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A database of funding for postdocs &amp; ECRs</title>
      <link>https://asntech.github.io/post/database-of-fundings-for-postdocs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2018 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://asntech.github.io/post/database-of-fundings-for-postdocs/</guid>
      <description>In early 2018, I became the eLife Ambassador along with more than 150 others to work to catalyse improvements in the way science is communicated and performed. I have joined the initiatives, with focus on;
 Science communication, publishing, funding, open access, open science, preprints, and reproducibility
 In the funding initiative, the eLife Ambassadors created a comprehensive Excel sheet of funding schemes and opportunities for postdocs and early career researchers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JASPAR database in a new look after 14 years</title>
      <link>https://asntech.github.io/post/jaspar-database-with-a-new-look/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://asntech.github.io/post/jaspar-database-with-a-new-look/</guid>
      <description>JASPAR is an open-access database of transcription factor binding profiles across multiple species in six taxonomic groups. It was first developed by Albin Sandelin during his Ph.D. at Karolinska Institutet, Sweden in 2004. JASPAR is an extremely useful resource for transcriptional gene regulation community, and it has been widely used and cited (&amp;gt;4,000 citations).
Since then JASPAR database has been extensively updated almost every second year. For the seventh release of JASPAR, I got involved to redevelop the entire database including its features and user interface.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time to make Venn diagrams UpSet</title>
      <link>https://asntech.github.io/post/time-to-make-venn-diagram-upset/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2017 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://asntech.github.io/post/time-to-make-venn-diagram-upset/</guid>
      <description>For decades Venn diagrams (created by John Venn in 1880) have been a primary way to show set intersections. Although Venn diagrams are very useful in set theory but not scalable if the number of sets increases more than four, it is very difficult to understand them. Also, it’s not possible to show more than 6 sets in a Venn diagram. For example, the below six-way Venn diagram shows the distribution of shared gene families among six genomes, taken from D’Hont et al.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to my new website using Hugo framework</title>
      <link>https://asntech.github.io/post/welcome/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://asntech.github.io/post/welcome/</guid>
      <description>This is a welcome post about my new website using Academic Theme and the Hugo</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>