<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Publishing on Aziz Khan</title>
    <link>https://asntech.github.io/tags/publishing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Publishing on Aziz Khan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2020 Aziz Khan</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2019 12:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://asntech.github.io/tags/publishing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>My worst Journal shopping and peer-review experience</title>
      <link>https://asntech.github.io/post/my-worst-journal-shopping-and-peer-review-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2019 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://asntech.github.io/post/my-worst-journal-shopping-and-peer-review-experience/</guid>
      <description>As an early career researcher it is not easy to publish your research in a decent scientific journal and with the time passes scientific publishing is becoming more difficult and challenging.
The aim of one of my initial projects during Ph.D. was to integrate diverse types of data to identify new signatures of a newly defined class of enhancers (super-enhancers) using computational and machine learning modeling. Through integrative analysis, we found some new features alongside with many known and ranked them based on their predictive importance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Towards a format-free submission policy: Let&#39;s put science first</title>
      <link>https://asntech.github.io/post/towards-a-format-free-initial-submission-policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Apr 2018 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://asntech.github.io/post/towards-a-format-free-initial-submission-policy/</guid>
      <description>Most academic journals have stringent manuscript formatting guidelines that authors must follow before making an initial submission. This process is extremely time consuming and, in many cases, has to be repeated multiple times for submission to a new journal after rejection.
 Formatting has no impact on the scientific basis of a manuscript, and style plays no role in the ability to judge its scientific content.
 It is, therefore, essential to stop these unnecessary and wasteful cycles of formatting to save time and resources.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>