<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Web App on Aziz Khan</title>
    <link>https://asntech.github.io/tags/web-app/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Web App on Aziz Khan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019 Aziz Khan</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/web-app/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>ECRcentral</title>
      <link>https://asntech.github.io/project/ecrcentral/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://asntech.github.io/project/ecrcentral/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ecrcentral.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;ECRcentral&lt;/a&gt; is a central platform for early career researchers to find research fellowships and travel grants, and to share experiences, resources and feedback.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ECRcentral is a community-driven initiative which was started by eLife Ambassadors 2018. The eLife Ambassador program supports the development of new initiatives ranging from preprints, reproducibility, and funding, by facilitating local discussions and connecting communities with international developments. We invite you to join and contribute by adding/editing funding opportunities. You can read more about how you can get involved here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The platform is developed using open source technology, with all source code and documentation available publically. All the source code and related content are openly available through our &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ecrcentral/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;GitHub repository&lt;/a&gt;, so the community can contribute and/or reuse the code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ECRcentral aims to bring early career researchers together to discuss funding opportunities, share experiences, and create impact through community engagement.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>mCrossBase</title>
      <link>https://asntech.github.io/project/mcrossbase/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://asntech.github.io/project/mcrossbase/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://zhanglab.c2b2.columbia.edu/mCrossBase/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;mCrossBase&lt;/a&gt; is a database of RNA-binding protein (RBP) binding motifs and crosslink sites defined jointly from CLIP data using a novel algorithm mCross (Feng et al. 2019 Mol. Cell, DOI: &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.molcel.2019.02.002&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.molcel.2019.02.002&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UniBind</title>
      <link>https://asntech.github.io/project/unibind/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://asntech.github.io/project/unibind/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;UniBind (&lt;a href=&#34;http://unibind.uio.no/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://unibind.uio.no/&lt;/a&gt;) is a comprehensive map of direct transcription factor (TF) – DNA interactions in the human genome. These interactions were obtained uniformly processing thousands of ChIP-seq data sets, from raw reads to high confidence TF binding site predictions, using the ChIP-eat software. ChIP-eat used the MACS2 peak caller to identify ChIP-seq peaks on the hg38 version of the human genome. Next, these genomic regions were analysed with four different TF binding prediction models to derive direct TF-DNA interactions. These models include DiMO-optimized position weight matrices (PWMs), transcription factor flexible models, DNA shape-based models, and binding energy models. An entropy-based algorithm was used to automatically delineate an enrichment zone containing direct TF – DNA interactions, supported by both strong computational evidence and strong experimental evidence. The UniBind database hosts the complete set of TFBS predictions for each prediction model, as well as the models themselves, the original ChIP-seq peaks, and cis-regulatory modules derived from these direct TF – DNA interactions.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JASPAR 2018</title>
      <link>https://asntech.github.io/project/jaspar-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://asntech.github.io/project/jaspar-2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;JASPAR is a widely used open-access database of curated, non-redundant transcription factor binding profiles. We have developed a brand new web interface using Django and also a REST API. The web app and REST API is implemented in Python using Django and Django REST Framework. It is accessible at &lt;a href=&#34;http://jaspar.genereg.net&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://jaspar.genereg.net&lt;/a&gt; and the source code is freely available at &lt;a href=&#34;https://bitbucket.org/CBGR/jaspar&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://bitbucket.org/CBGR/jaspar&lt;/a&gt; under GPL v3 license.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intervene Web App</title>
      <link>https://asntech.github.io/project/intervene-web-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://asntech.github.io/project/intervene-web-app/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Intervene Web App&lt;/strong&gt; is an interactive and user-friendly Shiny-based application for effective intersection and visualization of list/name sets as Venn diagram, UpSet plots, and heatmaps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Intervene&lt;/strong&gt; contains three modules:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;venn&lt;/strong&gt; to generate Venn diagrams of up to six sets,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;upset&lt;/strong&gt; to generate UpSet plots of multiple sets, and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;pairwise&lt;/strong&gt; to compute and visualize intersections of multiple sets as clustered heat maps.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Intervene provides an easy and interactive web interface to perform set analysis and generate publication-quality figures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Web application is available at:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://asntech.shinyapps.io/intervene&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://asntech.shinyapps.io/intervene&lt;/a&gt; OR&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://intervene.shinyapps.io/intervene/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://intervene.shinyapps.io/intervene/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the source code is freely available at:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/asntech/intervene-shiny&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://github.com/asntech/intervene-shiny&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A command line version to compute intersections of multiple genomic and list sets is available at: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/asntech/intervene&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://github.com/asntech/intervene&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
